ALICE HOUEL

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a Software Engineer with a winemaking background, who is passionate about music and making a positive social impact. Known for my audacity and tenacity, I love solving problems, learning new skills and sharing them, writing clean code and shipping features with a beautiful UX. As a Winemaker then and as an Engineer now, I deeply care about the quality of the product I craft and providing users with the best experience possible while improving their lives.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Mobile: +1 (503)703-6536Email: amhouel@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/alicehouel

GitHub: www.github.com/amhouel

• Website: amhouel.github.io

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Production planning (short- and long-term)
- Staff training & supervising
- Communication skills with multidisciplinary teams, suppliers & clients
- Professionalism
- Leadership

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend

HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | TypeScript | React | React Native | React Native Web | React Admin | Redux | GraphQL | Styled Components | CSS Modules

Backend

Node.js | Express | PostgreSQL & Sequelize | MongoDB & Mongoose | Hasura | Python

EDUCATION

General Assembly, New York

Web Development Immersive Certificate

University of Reims, Champagne-Ardenne, France

Master's Degree in Viticulture & Enology

Burgundy Business School, France

Master's Degree in Wine and Spirits International Marketing

Polytech'Lille, France

Master's Degree in Food Technology & Processing Engineering

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer, Reach Progress PBC, New York December 2018 – present

Early stage start-up developing a web and mobile organizing application for progressive grassroots political campaigns and non-profit organizations:

- Work in close collaboration with our Product Manager, UX
 Designer, Backend Engineers and Frontend colleagues in an agile environment
- Build new features and improve existing ones for our React/React Native Web/Redux/Expo apps
- Create reusable cross-platform components
- Convert our JavaScript codebase to TypeScript
- Fix bugs
- Review code
- Contribute on the Backend in Python

Teaching Assistant Volunteer, Code Nation, New York October 2019 - March 2020

Teacher Led Web Development Program at the Academy Of Innovative Technology:

- Helped 10th grade students understand/ learn HTML, CSS, JQuery and Javascript
- Guided the students in completing their homework and projects

Engineering Fellow, General Assembly, New York *July 2018 - October 2018*

12-week Web Development Immersive (WDI)

- Designed and built 4 projects
- Give Back NYC app
 - √ Volunteers can find volunteering opportunities in their community in NYC, log their experiences and rate them. Volunteers get points for each rated experience.
 - √ Full-stack, responsive, web application built with ReactJS, CSS flexbox and CSS grid, NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL and Sequelize ORM.
 - √ https://give-back-nyc.herokuapp.com

Winemaker, City Winery New York, New York February 2017 - July 2018

- Planned and supervised the production of City Winery's and our clients' white, rosé and red wines
- Hired, trained & managed permanent & seasonal workers (up to 15 each year) & new winemakers
- Collaborated with multi-disciplinary teams, suppliers & 5 clients